George Sugarman
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
George Sugarman papers
1912-2001
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Sugarman, George
6.9 linear feet
The papers of painter and sculptor George Sugarman measure 6.9 linear feet and date from 1912 to 2001, with the bulk of the material dating from 1959 to 1999. The collection documents Sugarman's career as a sculptor primarily through correspondence, project files, exhibition files, writings, and photographs. The collection also includes address and appointment books, business and financial records, and printed material.
Biographical Note
George Sugarman was a painter and sculptor who disliked labels because he believed they oversimplified the complexity of art, and Sugarman's artwork, like the artist himself, resists classification and oversimplification. Although he was influenced by Surrealist imagery, Cubist ideas of space, Baroque sculpture, and Abstract Expressionism, Sugarman's sculptures also display a musical quality, reflecting his interest in jazz music and improvisation. Sugarman was a pioneer in the use of color in sculpture and is probably best known for his large, polychrome aluminum sculptures.
Sugarman made the decision to become an artist relatively late in life. Born in New York on May 11, 1912, he studied at City College in New York and graduated with a B.A. in 1934. After serving in the United States Navy from 1941 until 1945, he attended evening classes at Museum of Modern Art. At the age of 39, George Sugarman traveled to Paris to study painting under the GI Bill of Rights. While in Paris, he decided to study sculpture with Ossip Zadkine and began creating wood carvings and terra-cotta sculptures. Over the next few years, Sugarman traveled to Italy and Spain, studying Baroque sculpture and architecture. He was particularly attracted to the work of Bernini and to Bernini's use of space.
Sugarman returned to New York in 1955 and began working with laminated wood. In order to support himself, he accepted a job teaching carpentry at a private school. He joined the Brata Gallery in 1957 and helped found the New Sculpture Group. A few years later, Sugarman received major recognition of his work by winning second prize in sculpture at the Pittsburgh International Exhibition. Sugarman went on to win a Longview Foundation Grant, a Ford Foundation Grant for his work at the Tamarind Lithography Workshop, and a grant from the National Endowment for the Arts.
In the 1960s, Sugarman began working on large painted-aluminum sculptures and completed his first outdoor sculpture at the Xerox Building in El Segundo, Calif. in 1969. Many of Sugarman's outdoor sculptures generated intense controversy, particularly his sculpture for the Edward A. Garmatz Federal Building and Courthouse in Baltimore, but he was devoted to his belief in the social as well as aesthetic importance of public art. Sugarman saw public sculpture as a "metaphor for the human condition" and as a way to transcend what he called the "indoor eye," the eye which views art in isolation from its physical and social environment.
Sugarman taught at the Graduate School of Hunter College in New York City from 1960 until 1970 and served as visiting Associate Professor at the Yale University Graduate School of Art from 1967 to 1968. Sugarman was a prolific artist, participating in numerous one-man shows, group exhibitions, and competitions all over the world, yet recognition of his talent came almost a decade later in the United States than in Europe. His works are in major collections including the Museum of Modern Art, the Whitney Museum of American Art, and the Art Institute of Chicago. George Sugarman died on August 25, 1999.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of painter and sculptor George Sugarman measure 6.9 linear feet and date from 1912 to 2001, with the bulk of the material dating from 1959 to 1999. The collection documents Sugarman's career as a sculptor primarily through correspondence, project files, exhibition files, writings, and photographs. The collection also includes address and appointment books, business and financial records, and printed material.
The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence with family members, friends, artists, and scholars, reflecting Sugarman's diverse influences and interests. The project files and exhibition files illustrate Sugarman's prolific career as an artist and document Sugarman's numerous projects and exhibitions abroad, particularly in Japan.
The writings by Sugarman are noteworthy as they reveal the integral relationship between Sugarman's philosophical theories about art and his actual works of art. The business and financial records mainly document expenses incurred while working on various projects and exhibitions and while traveling. Maps, clippings, and brochures from Sugarman's many travels are included as well as exhibition catalogs and announcements for Sugarman and others. The collection also contains photographs of George Sugarman and his artwork, dating mostly from the 1970s.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into nine series. Series are arranged by type of material; materials within series are arranged alphabetically by name or by type of material and then chronologically.
Series 1: Biographical Materials, 1912-2000, n.d. (Box 1; 9 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1959-2001, n.d. (Boxes 1-3, OV 8; 2.9 linear feet)
Series 3: Project Files, 1968-1997, n.d. (Boxes 3-4; 1 linear foot)
Series 4:: Exhibition Files, 1965-1993, n.d. (Boxes 4-5, OV 8; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 5: Writings, 1951-1992, n.d. (Box 5; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 6: Address and Appointment Books, 1972-1997, n.d. (Boxes 5-6; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 7: Business and Financial Records, 1962-1998, n.d. (Box 6; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 8: Printed Material, 1954-1999, n.d. (Boxes 6-7, OV 8; 1.2 linear feet)
Series 9: Photographs, 1966-1981, n.d. (Box 7; 0.2 linear feet)
Related Material
The transcript and audiotapes of an interview with George Sugarman conducted by Paul Cummings in 1974 for the Archives of American Art's Oral History Program is available at the Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution.
Separated Material
Materials loaned by George Sugarman in 1970 are available on microfilm reels N70-50 and N70-51. Reel N70-50 contains biographical material, an essay about George Sugarman, exhibition catalogs and announcements dating from 1954 to 1960, a certificate, writings by Sugarman, and correspondence dating from 1953 to 1970. The originals of most of those materials are included in the papers later donated. Reel N70-50 also contains a substantial number of photographs of Sugarman's natural wood sculptures from the late 1950s, his early works in wood, clay, and plaster dating from 1951 to 1958, his drawings and paintings from the late 1960s, installations and works in progress from 1960 to 1970, and photographs of Sugarman working in the studio in the 1960s. Many of these photographs were not included in the later gift of papers. Reels N70-50 and N70-51 contain twelve sketchbooks and loose pages dating from 1943 to 1958 which document Sugarman's travels to the South Pacific, New York City, France, Spain, and North Africa.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects-Topical:
Sculpture, Modern -- 20th century -- New York (State) -- New York; Sculptors -- New York (State) -- New York -- Interviews
Types of Materials:
Photographs; Sound recordings; Interviews; Drawings
Names:
Jaffe, Shirley, 1923-; Honegger, Gottfried, 1917-; Kushner, Robert, 1949-
Provenance
In 1970, George Sugarman lent material to the Archives of American Art for microfilming. In 1980 and 1983, George Sugarman donated portions of the material previously lent, along with additional materials. Additional materials were donated by Sugarman's niece, Arden Sugarman Eilopolous, in 1999 and 2000.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Microfilmed portion must be consulted on microfilm. Use of unmicrofilmed portion requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington, D.C. research facility.
Alternative Forms Available
The loaned materials are available on microfilm reels N70-50 and N70-51. The microfilm is available for interlibrary loan.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1912-2000, undated, Series 1:; (Box 1; 9 folders)
  The series contains certificates, documents, and identification cards relating to Sugarman's educational, military, and work experiences. A few letters are included as well as lists of exhibitions and projects, a comprehensive bibliography, and a transcript of Sugarman's interview with Steve Davis in 1997. The series is arranged alphabetically by type of material and then chronologically.
  - Certificates, 1912-1977 (Box 1)
  - Employment Information, 1935-1951 (Box 1)
  - Interview Transcript, 1997, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Membership and Identification Cards, 1942-2000, undated (Box 1)
  - Military Service Information, 1945-1954 (Box 1)
  - Passports, 1951-1994, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1968-2000, undated (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1959-2001, undated, Series 2:; (Boxes 1-3, OV 8; 2.9 linear feet)
  Found in this series is personal correspondence from family members and friends and professional correspondence from colleges and universities relating to Sugarman's many teaching positions. Correspondence from art dealers, art suppliers, and gallery owners is also included. Notable correspondents include Gottfried Honegger, Shirley Jaffe, and Robert Kushner. Correspondence relating to specific projects or exhibitions is also found in the Project Files and the Exhibition Files.
  The majority of files are arranged alphabetically by correspondent's personal name. Some of the files were originally arranged alphabetically by business or organizational name. The original arrangement was preserved when there were multiple correspondents from one organization. Those files are mostly from galleries, universities, and art suppliers. Correspondents with fewer than five items are filed alphabetically in miscellaneous folders.
  - Unidentifiable and Illegible, 1961-1996, undated (Box 1)
  - First Names Only, 1954-1999, undated, (5 folders) (Box 1)
  - Armstrong, Richard, 1983-1992, undated (Box 1)
  - Aronson, Leonard, 1970-1973 (Box 1)
  - Augustyn, Rafai, 1986-1996 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous A: Adelman-Anderson-McQuoid, 1968-1986 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous A: Andrews-Awad, 1971-1979, undated (Box 1)
  - Bishop, Budd, 1975-1979, undated (Box 1)
  - Bourdon, Robert, 1977-1982, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous B: Banque-Berriolo, 1973-1999, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous B: Bertoldi-Borras, 1961-1998, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous B: Bozo-Butler, 1965-1984, undated (Box 1)
  - Capurso, Peter, 1971-1998, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Chill, Vivian, 1981-1985, undated (Box 1)
  - Clareboudt, Jean, 1992-1995 (Box 1)
  - Collier, Ric, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Cutting, Jennifer McGregor, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous C: Canady/Eagle-Ceredi, 1961-1997, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous C: Champlin-Cole, 1970-1994, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous C: Coleman-Cummings, 1964-1991 (Box 1)
  - Davies, Brian, 1995, (contains photographs) (Box 1)
  - Davis, Brad, 1972-1996, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Davis, Evelyn, 1972-1990, undated, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Day, Holliday, 1981-1997, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Deyab, Larry, 1992-1997 (Box 1)
  - Doll, Don, S.J., 1978, (Creighton U.) (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous D: Danto-Dee, 1975-1999, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous D: Delaney-Dreyer, 1960-1992, undated (Box 1)
  - Eilopoulos, Arden, 1971-1994, (6 folders) (Box 1)
  - Elsen, Albert, 1980-1989, undated (Box 1)
  - Everett, Roxanne, 1971-1995, undated, (3 folders; see also Lippincott, Inc.) (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous E: Ebihara-Emery, 1974-1996, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous E: Emmerich-English, 1970-1997 (Box 1)
  - Fischbach Gallery, 1967-1970, undated (Box 1)
  - Frank, Liz, 1982-1986 (Box 1)
  - French, Steve, 1983-1984, undated (Box 1)
  - Fuller, Diane, 1984-1987, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous F: Faber-Foote, 1975-1998, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous F: Forgach-Fundacio Antoni Tapies, 1967-1990, undated (Box 1)
  - Galerie Alfred Schmela, 1969-1970, undated (Box 1)
  - Galerie Rudolph Zwirner, 1981 (Box 1)
  - General Adjustment Bureau, Inc., 1967-1968 (Box 1)
  - (Box 2)
  - Geske, Norman, 1970-1972 (Box 2)
  - Giza, Robert, 1985, undated (Box 2)
  - Goldin, Amy, 1970-1972, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous G: Gallager-Geldzahler, 1982-1985 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous G: Giddens-Greenberg, 1966-1994 (Box 2)
  - Haerer, Carol, 1981-1985 (Box 2)
  - Harper, Paula, 1980-1996, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Hayashi, Yoko, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
  - Higuchi, Shoichiro, 1992-1995 (Box 2)
  - Hodge, G. Stuart, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Hoffeld, Jeffrey, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Honegger, Gottfried, 1961-1992 (Box 2)
  - Hunter College, City University of New York, 1960-1970 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous H: Haber-Hennessey, 1971-1995 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous H: Hesse-Honegger-Holt, 1975-1992 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous H: Hompson-Huot, 1972-1985 (Box 2)
  - Iino, Kiichi, 1993-1994 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous I: Iijima-International Sculpture Center, 1973-1996 (Box 2)
  - Jacobs, Kenneth, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - Jaffe, Shirley, 1970-1997, undated, (9 folders) (Box 2)
  - Jakmauh, Ed, 1982-1992 (Box 2)
  - Jassaud, Gervais, 1992-1996, undated (Box 2)
  - Knoebel, David, 1985-1989, undated (Box 2)
  - Koshalek, Richard, 1977-1978, undated (Box 2)
  - Kulicke, Barbara, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Kushner, Robert, 1974-1984, undated (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous K: Kaletsch-Kaufman, 1976-1998, undated (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous K: Kearns-Kerns, 1968-1994 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous K: Kilroy-Kramer, 1961-1993, undated (Box 2)
  - Lanchner, Carolyn, 1971-2001, undated, (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Lane, Allison, 1992-1995, undated (Box 2)
  - Lavater, Warja, 1970-1995, (2 folders; see also Honegger, Gottfried) (Box 2)
  - Levy, Ester, 1972-1985, undated (Box 2)
  - Lippincott, Inc., 1968-1982, undated, (5 folders) (Box 2)
  - Little, Deborah, 1971-1999, undated, (6 folders) (Box 2)
  - Lüscher, Ingeborg, 1979-1992, undated (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous L: Lafaye-Lanners, 1980-1999 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous L: Laux-Linton, 1972-1985 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous L: Loeb-Lutz, 1971-1979 (Box 2)
  - Matalon, Edward, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Miami-Dade Community College, 1970-1975, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Mitelberg, Zuka, 1972-1998, (9 folders) (Box 2)
  - Moorhead State College, 1970-1972 (Box 2)
  - Morita, Kim, 1993-1995, undated (Box 2)
  - Müller, Fridolin and Elspeth, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Myers, Mary, 1975-1979, undated (Box 2)
  - Myers, Ruth, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous M: Mannes-McWilliams, 1971-1992, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous M: Medinger-Mitterand, 1977-1999, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous M: Mondale-Motz, 1970-1997 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous M: Mulhern-Myers, 1972-1989 (Box 3)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, 1966-1985 (Box 3)
  - Northwestern University, 1976-1985 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous N: Nachi-Norman, 1970-1991, undated (Box 3)
  - Osabe, Yuki, 1990-1995, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous O: Olausen-Owens, 1970-1985 (Box 3)
  - Purdue University, 1974-1975 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous P: Palevsky-Pickering, 1971-1981 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous P: Pines-Portell, 1966-1999, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous P: Pounders-Public Library of Columbus, 1974-1988 (Box 3)
  - Queens College, the City of University of New York, 1972-1973, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Radich, Stephen, 1959-1967, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Rudans, Eriks, 1971-1978, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous R: Ralph-Reyes, 1961-1996 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous R: Rhodes-Royce, 1961-1986, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous R: Rubin-Ryoko, 1970-1994, undated (Box 3)
  - Saint-Cloud State College, 1969-1971, undated (Box 3)
  - San Jose Museum of Art, 1999 (Box 3)
  - San Jose State University, 1982-1984 (Box 3)
  - Schwartz, Joyce Pomeroy, 1993-1999, undated (Box 3)
  - Scott, John C., Jr., 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - Shovers, Reva, 1975-1991, undated, (4 folders) (Box 3)
  - Städtisches Museum Leverkusen, 1970-1975, undated (Box 3)
  - State University of New York at Oneonta, 1970-1972 (Box 3)
  - State University of New York at Potsdam, 1971-1972, undated (Box 3)
  - Sugarman, Ira, 1970-1999, undated, (5 folders) (Box 3)
  - Suynam, Jane, 1973-1978 (Box 3)
  - Szeemann, Harald, 1963-1990, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous S: Samter-Schutz, 1970-1998, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous S: Sellers-Seybolt, 1976-1992 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous S: Shanley-Shimoda, 1971-1995, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous S: Silverman-Solomon, 1972-1989, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous S: Spiegel-Storr, 1972-1997, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous S: Straum-Swetz, 1953-1998, undated (Box 3)
  - Taylor, John (Jock), 1972-1976, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Thalacker, Donald, 1976-1987, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Thomas, Tamara, undated (Box 3)
  - Tilitz, Robert, 1978-1994, undated (Box 3)
  - Tisb, Pauline, 1972-1978, undated (Box 3)
  - Tramatela, 1981-1984, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous T: Taylor-Thompson, 1966-1984, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous T: Tillett-Tuchman, 1974-1992 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous U-V: Unber-Vassar, 1976-1996 (Box 3)
  - Webster, Sally, 1986-1991, undated (Box 3)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art1980-1986, undated (Box 3)
  - Williams, Anthony, 1995, (see OV 8) (Box 3)
  - Withers, Josephine, 1982-1991, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous W: Waldman-Weiley, 1973-1998 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous W: Welish-Westreich, 1977-1983, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous W: Wetenhall-Wofford1961-1992, undated (Box 3)
  - Yoshida, Miya, 1993-1995, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Y: Yale-Yunkers, 1967-1995, undated (Box 3)
  - Zabriskie Gallery, 1974-1977, undated, (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Ziegler, Maurice and Renee, 1966-1994 (Box 3)
  - Zucker, Barbara, 1985-1988, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Z: Zack-Zwick, 1975-1977, undated (Box 3)
  - Williams, Anthony, 1995 (Box OV 8)
- Project Files, 1968-1997, undated, Series 3:; (Boxes 3-4; 1 linear foot)
  Correspondence, contracts, drawings, receipts, and printed material relating to completed and proposed sculpture projects are included in the series. Some of the major projects represented include: the Edward A. Garmatz Federal Building and U.S. Courthouse in Baltimore, Md. (1974-1978), Columbia Plaza in Cincinnati, Ohio (1983-1985), and the Miyazaki Prefectural Museum of Art in Japan (1994-1995.) Materials relating to Sugarman's participation in the Tamarind Lithography Workshop are also included in the series. The files are arranged alphabetically by the name of the project and then chronologically. Large files are subdivided by type of material.
  - Albany South Mall, New York, 1970-1979, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Albert M. Greenfield School, Philadelphia, Pa., 1971-1973, undated (Box 3)
  - Allegheny Landing Park, Pittsburgh, Pa., 1983-1985, (4 folders) (Box 3)
  - Bellevue Park, Wichita Falls, Texas, 1981-1982, undated, (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - Columbia Plaza, Cincinnati, Ohio, 1983-1985, undated, (7 folders) (Box 4)
  - Crystal Tower, Kobe, Japan, 1992-1997, undated, (6 folders) (Box 4)
  - Detroit Recieving Hospital and University Medical Center, Michigan, 1977-1984, undated, (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - Doris Freedman Sculpture Plaza, New York, N.Y., 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Edward A. Garmatz Federal Building and U.S. Courthouse, Baltimore, Md., 1974-1979, undated, (18 folders) (Box 4)
  - Federal Reserve System Building, Washington, D.C., 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - First National Bank of Saint Paul, Minn., 1968-1975, undated, (5 folders) (Box 4)
  - Friedman Project, Mayfield Village, Ohio, 1989, undated (Box 4)
  - Honolulu Municipal Office Building, Hawaii, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - Horvitz Family Home, Cleveland, Ohio, 1986-1989, undated (Box 4)
  - Interfirst Plaza, Dallas, Texas, 1983, undated (Box 4)
  - Iowa City Civic Center, Iowa, 1974, undated (Box 4)
  - Lincoln National Life Insurance Company Building, Fort Wayne, Ind., 1975-1978, undated, (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - Markborough California Properties, Inc., san Francisco, Calif., 1989-1990, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Miami International Airport, Florida, 1976-1981, undated, (4 folders) (Box 4)
  - Mitsui Marine, Tokyo, Japan, 1994, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Miyazaki Prefectural Musuem of Art, Japan, 1994-1995, undated, (12 folders) (Box 4)
  - Nebraska Interstate 80 Bicentennial, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - Palm Springs House, California, 1970-1971 (Box 4)
  - Southern California Metro Rail, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Southland Center, Dallas, Texas, 1983, undated (Box 4)
  - Tamarind Lithography Workshop, Los Angeles, Calif., 1965 (Box 4)
  - Veterans Administration Medical Center, Gainesville, Fla., 1980-1985, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Wills Eye Hospital, Philadelphia, Pa., 1979-1982, undated, (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - Xerox Building, El Segundo, Calif., 1968-1969, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4)
- Exhibition Files, 1965-1993, undated, Series 4:; (Box 5, OV 8; 0.6 linear feet)
  The series contains correspondence, shipping invoices and receipts, loan agreements, clippings, and exhibition catalogs and announcements relating to Sugarman's exhibitions. Major exhibitions represented in the series include: the George Sugarman retrospective, 1969-1970, the Shape of Space: the Sculpture of George Sugarman exhibition, 1981-1982, and the Osaka Triennale exhibitions, 1992-1993. Also included are two audiocassettes of an interview and a lecture done in conjunction with the opening of the Shape of Space exhibition in 1981.
  The series is divided into general exhibition files and specific exhibition files. The general exhibition files are arranged chronologically and contain materials primarily concerning Sugarman's smaller exhibitions. The specific exhibition files are arranged alphabetically by the title of the exhibition and then chronologically. Exhibition dates are expressed in parentheses, with the dates of the documentation following.
  - Exhibitions, General, 1967-1993, undated, (17 folders) (Box 5)
  - "11th Biennial of Outdoor Sculpture" (1971), 1971 (Box 5)
  - 200 Years of American Sculpture (1976), 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - "Abstract Expressionism: The Third Dimension" (1984-1985), 1984 (Box 5)
  - Artist & Fabricator (1975), 1975 (Box 5)
  - L'Art Vivant aux Etats-Unis (1970), 1970 (Box 5)
  - Color in Art: American Expressions from the Mid-Twentieth Century to the Present (1990), 1990 (Box 5)
  - Contemporary Sculpture Center Exhibition (1994), 1993-1994, (3 folders) (Box 5)
  - The Decorative Impulse (1979-1980), 1979 (Box 5)
  - George Sugarman (1969-1970), 1969-1972, (6 folders) (Box 5)
  - "George Sugarman: Sculpture" (1981), 1981 (Box 5)
  - "Osaka Triennale '92" (1992), 1992 (Box 5)
  - "Osaka Triennale '93" (1993), 1993 (Box 5)
  - "Painted Sculpture" (1980), 1980 (Box 5)
  - "Paintings and Sculpture by George Sugarman" (1977), 1977-1978 (Box 5)
  - "The Sculpture of George Sugarman" (1981), 1980-1981, (see also OV 8; 3 folders) (Box 5)
  - Shape of Space: the Sculpture of George Sugarman (1981-1982), 1980-1982, (3 folders) (Box 5)
  - "The Small Sculpture Show" (1977), 1976-1978 (Box 5)
  - The Society of the Four Arts Sculpture Competition Exhibition (1974-1975), 1974-1975 (Box 5)
  - The Tenth Street Days - the Coops of the 50's (1977-1980), 1977-1980 (Box 5)
  - "Twenty-Three Recent Drawings by George Sugarman" (1971), 1971 (Box 5)
  - "Useable Art" (1980-1982), 1980-1982 (Box 5)
  - Wood-Works (1974), 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - "The Sculpture of George Sugarman" (1981), 1981 (Box OV 8)
- Writings, 1951-1992, undated, Series 5:; (Box 5; 0.2 linear feet)